Live large
Marmaduke is a family, comedy film directed by Tom Dey.
When Phil and Debbie Winslow relocate from their native Kansas to the sunny climes of Orange County, their
big-hearted, havoc-wreaking Great Dane gets a taste of the dog's life, California-style.
Marmaduke (voice), played by Owen Wilson.
Mazie (voice), played by Emma Stone.
Carlos (voice), played by George López.
Barbara Winslow, played by Caroline Sunshine.
Brian Winslow, played by Finley Jacobsen.
Raisin (voice), played by Steve Coogan.
Marmaduke is a 2010 American comedy film based on Brad
Anderson's comic strip of the same name.
The film was directed by Tom Dey and stars an ensemble cast consisting of Owen
Wilson (as the title character), Lee Pace, Judy Greer, William H.
Macy, Steve Coogan, Sam Elliott, Fergie, George Lopez, Christopher
Mintz-Plasse, Emma Stone, Kiefer Sutherland, and Marlon Wayans.
It centers on a Great Dane named Marmaduke (voiced by Wilson) who moves with his family
from Kansas to Orange County and faces challenges to fit in with other dogs.
The film was released in the United States on June 4, 2010, by 20th Century Fox.
It received generally negative reviews from critics and grossed $89.9
million worldwide against a production budget of $50 million.
An animated sequel was released in 2022.
The film explores themes of based on comic, slapstick comedy,
dog, great dane, orange county, california.
The tone is lighthearted.